For three days each summer, Britain has a gathering unlike any other - a celebration of country sport that draws visitors in their tens of thousands.
Hunting, shooting, fishing... ..conservation and kayaking too - it's all here at the CLA Game Fair.
The Country Land and Business Association's annual game fair is one of the biggest events in the rural calendar.
This year, it comes from the magnificent Harewood House in West Yorkshire.
It is quite a setting.
We'll be soaking up the atmosphere and going behind the scenes... ..bringing you a flavour of what's on offer.
I'm hoping my dog, Oscar, can pick up some skills like these.
'But it's not looking good.'
Whilst I'll be joining the ladies... ..showing the men how it's done.
Complete natural.
Also, Tom's in the majestic Scottish Highlands.
Huge swathes of this wild country have been in the same families for generations, but dramatic changes to land ownership could change all that.
But will it help Scotland's rural communities?
I'll be finding out.
And Adam is also here in Yorkshire.
I'm on the trail of Yorkshire's county breeds and these local beauties are known by some as the world's favourite pig.
But what made them so popular?
This is the CLA Game Fair 2015 - a true celebration of the British countryside.
If you're interested in horses and hounds, country crafts, fishing, falconry or ferrets, this is the place to be.
We are in the grounds of Harewood House in west Yorkshire, just eight miles north of Leeds.
The site here on the Harewood estate is huge, but then it has to be, because this is the biggest moveable countryside event in the world.
Amazing!
This year's game fair spans across 500 acres of the estate, and they are expecting to welcome 150,000 visitors over the weekend.
The planning and preparation for this started more than 18 months ago, and yet the whole build is done by just 26 people.
And to keep things running smoothly, you need people like Tony - and here is the main man himself.
Tony, how are you?
Hello, Anita.
How are you?
I'm fine, thank you.
The organiser of the whole affair.
How is it looking today?
It's looking...
When I consider we had 40 hours of rain between Sunday and Tuesday, and I don't have an enormous team, I have to say, it looks absolutely fabulous already.
How long has the game fair been running?
58 years - it started with a budget of £850.
I would be frightened to tell you how much it is now.
No, go on, tell me.
It's certainly well over...
It's close on £5 million to put the show on.
Wow.
What goes on at the game fair?
It's a celebration of the countryside.
So it is guns, it is fishing, it is shopping.
We become...
I think it's the seventh largest retail area in the country for this weekend.
It's a real celebration of the culture of the countryside, isn't it?
You don't have to be have a 4x4 and a wardrobe full of tweed to come here.
No.
Although there is a heck of a lot of tweed here!
There certainly is.
And on a hot day, I do admire anybody who wears it.
We encourage all walks of life to come to the show, because that is something for everybody, I really do...
I'm not saying that because I'm talking to you.
It really is true.
Have a "gander" at this!
'And, yes, before you write in, I know they're ducks.'
There is so much going on down here, and overseeing it all is that magnificent house just over there.
Joe is having a quick look inside.
Harewood House is incredible - 181 rooms of exquisitely crafted, restored and preserved history.
This 18th-century house was designed, built and decorated by the absolute best of the best at the time.
Now, this is the gallery - it's nearly 80 feet long and isn't it a magnificent space?
Now, local Thomas Chippendale designed all the original furniture here at the house and, if you look above the windows and you see these ornate curtain designs, they were actually made by his son.
But, incredibly, they are not made of cloth - they are actually carved from wood.
There are three libraries in the house, together holding more than 11,000 books.
This one is the Spanish library, complete with Chippendale steps - well, it wouldn't be a library without them, would it?
The walls around the house are adorned with wonderful art, with some pieces painted especially for the family.
Just look at this beautiful painting of the house.
It was painted only 20 years after the house was built and it's an incredibly romantic vision.
And guess who the creator was?
It was a young Turner, who was relatively unknown, just at the start of his career and, if you come with me, you can see the very hill where he would have been, in this beautiful landscape - of course, designed by Capability Brown - which, today, is housing the game fair.
And if you have the eyesight of the game fair falcon, you might just be able to pick out Anita somewhere down there.
I'm just here, Joe.
Working very hard... having ice cream.
The incredible gardens really are the perfect backdrop for the fair.
The view is magnificent - as is the ice cream.
As you'd expect, there are landowners here from across the country enjoying the fair.
But, as Tom has been finding out, those from Scotland may have other things on their minds.
Scotland - for centuries, people battled for ownership of its vast and varied landscapes.
The great Scottish clans fought with each other and the English over land.
The crofters' claims to land were literally swept away by the Highland Clearances of the 18th and 19th centuries.
Who owns and uses the mountains, hills and fields here has shaped the history of Scotland.
And now, the battle cry can be heard again in Edinburgh, home of the Scottish Parliament.
The SNP has set its sights on big landowners and wants to open up their private world to the masses.
..Give effect to our commitments.
The government intends to embark on a radical programme of land reform.
Presiding Officer, Scotland's land must be an asset that benefits the many, not the few.
So, who are the few?
Well, just 432 individuals own half of Scotland's private land.
The SNP and their leader, Nicola Sturgeon, thinks that is outdated and unfair so they're planning to change it with a Land Reform Bill.
But before getting into the details of the bill, I need to understand the background.
I'm heading to the Hebridean island of Eigg to find out.
Colin Carr has been a tenant farmer for more than 25 years.
He farms sheep and beef, whilst wife Marie runs a bed and breakfast.
'He used to run the farm in partnership 'with a former landlord, 'but their relationship turned sour.'
His circumstances changed, and then he actually wanted the house we were running...staying in and running as a bed-and-breakfast...
He wanted that back.
And if we didn't comply...basically, then he tried to terminate the farming partnership as well.
'Although he was never evicted from his home, 'Colin felt he couldn't plan for the future 'or invest in his business.'
It was quite difficult, because there was no security - you didn't really know how long you were going to be here or how many...
What difficulties you were going to have with him.
So it all got a bit bad, really.
Stories like Colin's are the reason why the Scottish government has proposed sweeping reforms.
They include improved rights for tenant farmers, removal of tax exemption for shooting and deerstalking and, in extreme cases, ministers could actually force the sale of land.
And that has enraged landowners, some even likening it to Zimbabwe, when farmers were forced off their land.
'I put this to the SNP's Richard Lochhead.'
So, is this a Mugabe-style land grab?
People who oppose land reform usually have a vested interest, and they tend to be the people who talk about land grabs - no-one else is talking about land grabs.
This is about fairness, equality, giving communities and, indeed, in some cases, perhaps tenant farmers, individuals working on land, the opportunity to have a better life, more say over their own future.
It's about the government having the power to take land away...from owners.
What the legislation proposes is under certain circumstances, where there's clearly no other option that will move things forward, the government, yes, will take the opportunity to intervene.
Fighting talk from the SNP.
But communities taking control is nothing new.
Look at the island of Eigg, where I met Colin earlier - back in the 1990s, residents got so fed up with the succession of absentee landlords, they ended up buying their island.
The price tag - £1.5 million.
Eigg could be the poster child for the SNP's land reforms - they want a million acres under community ownership, just like this, by 2020 and the government plan to put aside £10 million to encourage similar community buyouts.
It certainly worked out for farmer Colin.
He's now got a permanent lease with the island trust, which has given him enough financial security to refurbish his rented home.
And you wouldn't have done this kind of work under the old regime.
Not a chance.
They wouldn't have invested in it and we wouldn't have had the confidence to go in like we did with the trust.
Yeah - oh, it's great.
The islanders of Eigg have been able to invest in a new ferry terminal to boost tourist numbers, and the latest in solar and wind power, making the island virtually self-sufficient in electricity.
Lancashire lass Maggie Fyffe moved to Eigg in the late 1970s, becoming one of the founders of the island trust.
People want to develop the island and, you know, the various aspects of it, but they're not being given the chance at the moment.
What do you think about the proposals that are now in front of the Scottish Parliament?
I think anything that makes it easier for communities like us to do what we've done is all to the better, it really is.
You know, a good landlord has nothing to fear from the legislation.
People might look at this and think it's all very easy - is it?
No, I wouldn't call it easy!
No, it was really, really hard work and it's hard work...you know, keeping the whole show running.
Survival hinges on the finances and some buyouts have struggled to make ends meet.
The island of Gigha was transferred to the community in 2002, but hit the headlines when they were dealing with debts of nearly £3 million.
They're managing, but it's a potential warning to others looking to do the same.
So, do tenants have the skills and experience to take over from their landlords?
Far from being absent or lazily looking down from their castles, many landlords say they are preserving their estates and the communities within them.
So, should we be keeping the status quo for the sake of rural Scotland?
That's what I'll be finding out later.
Today, we are at the CLA Game Fair on the Harewood estate near Leeds.
When you wander around a fair like this, one that is so focused on game hunting, you don't naturally think about wildlife conservation, but I've been told that the two can go hand-in-hand.
Roger Draycott is a biologist from the Game And Wildlife Conservation Trust.
Roger, surely people here are more interested in shooting game than preserving it?
Well, really, Anita, if you're interested in shooting pheasants, then to run a successful peasant shoot, you have to be managing all the habitats that the pheasants need really well, otherwise the shoot simply won't be successful.
And how would you do that?
Well, in woodlands, that is managing the understory to create this nice, shrubby cover, that lots of other birds are going to benefit from, but then if you move into the farmland, then we tend to grow lots of crops like this.
Right, I know what this is - this is quinoa - because I like to eat it.
Well, I would call this quin-o-ah!
A wonderful crop to provide cover for pheasants and partridges in the winter and it also provides an abundance of seed food as well.
It produces lots of feeding plants for pollinators, things like butterflies, bumblebees, honeybees, that we all know are suffering as well.
The goal is for more habitat like this.
So I'm leaving the crowds behind to head for a quiet spot on the estate, where an amazing transformation is taking place.
It is a wild corner that has been turned around by Christopher Usher.
Like his father before him, Christopher is the estate manager here at Harewood.
It is so beautiful here, Christopher.
It feels like we've entered another world.
We have, I suppose, in many ways - in two ways, really.
We're on the north-east side of the estate on one of our arable farms down at Stockton and in terms of another world, you are right in one context, because when I was a boy, all this was desert sort of farming - huge areas of growing...
Where we are standing now, it was growing corn, whereas now, as you can see, we've got a pond here, a pond there, bulrushes, we've got fantastic, diversified habitat.
All the hedgerows you've seen around here are new, the forestry strip going over there...
So these trees are not...
They haven't been here for centuries?
Absolutely not.
They're probably 15 years old, part of the Farm Woodland Premium Scheme when they were planted.
It's hard to imagine it was anything other than this, because it feels so natural - it works.
It makes a wildlife corridor and a link - by creating this habitat, and the incentives on the back of the shoot doing a lot of that, we've got this great area back again.
I think that's where I'm slightly conflicted - it's this idea of all of this wonderful conservation work to bring back the wildlife and create this fantastic natural habitat for then to...shoot it and kill it.
But look wider - I think we should need to look wider than shooting.
We've invested in our barn owl population, there's a barn owl box, to the right here.
We've got a great brown hare population here, plus, of course, all the songbirds that benefit, the pollen and nectar mixing here, the beetles and other insects and amphibians and everything else that will be here, too, on the back of it.
Everyone benefits and we perhaps shoot 40 ducks a year from it and enjoy eating them.
So not every bird on the estate is there for the guns.
Christopher and his team are working to increase the numbers of one of our most endangered wild birds - the grey partridge.
I suppose it wouldn't be Yorkshire if we didn't have a bit of rain.
We've lost 90% of our only native partridge in the last 100 years, mostly due to loss of habitat.
'Harewood's head gamekeeper, Tim Rothwell, 'is trying to buck that trend 'and he's called upon some unusual help.'
So, you've got quite a special way of feeding these grey partridges, haven't you?
What do you do?
That's right - we use broody hens.
Banties, mainly.
The hens are essentially fostering the grey partridges, aren't they?
Doing it like this, I can get more chicks from one hen partridge.
There was three pairs on the estate when I came, just on one farm on the estate.
And now?
We've got 15 pairs, and that is right across the estate as well, so...
You've increased the numbers fivefold, but 15 pairs still doesn't seem like many, does it?
And you've got lots of chicks here in these runs, so what happens to them?
Some of those will migrate onto neighbouring farms.
There's a saying - you've got to stock your neighbours before your own estate gets stocked.
For every hundred you put out, you might only keep five pairs on the estate.
So once you've got the numbers that you're looking for, what happens to the birds?
Are they there to be shot?
No, they're not, that's not the purpose of the project.
It's just our way of getting a few back on the estate, back into the countryside.
Do they have an identity crisis?
Do they grow up thinking they're hens and not partridges?
They create their own little family units, called a covey.
So in this coop here, we've got some that are about three weeks old.
They're all ready to be run through into the A-frame, so they'll have a bit more room.
There comes the first little one.
Come on...ooh!
Once one goes through, you'll get...the others will follow.
The hen is beautiful.
And they're in.
Right - so, they'll have a great time for a few more weeks.
Until they go out into the big wide world.
They just need some nice weather as well.
Well, it's Yorkshire, so...
They'll be hardy birds anyway, reared in Yorkshire.
It's been all over the news in recent days that one of the big issues in farming is the crisis in the dairy industry.
We've been following one young farmer to find out what falling milk prices mean to her and why she decided to take action.
I'm Becky Robertson.
I run a small family dairy farm in south Gloucestershire.
We have 100 Holsteins and the milk price is threatening my farm.
For 26-year-old Becky, her first year as a dairy farmer has been tough.
But while many struggling farmers have been forced to leave the industry, she is determined to have a future in a job she loves.
We've got a couple of heifers in here which are due to have their first babies and then the rest are, sort of, second, third, fourth calvers and, basically, they're on a two-month holiday before they have their babies.
We love our cows and, of course, we want to survive.
We've gone from 32p down to 21p within a matter of a year and if this price carries on or gets even lower, like there's talks of it happening, there won't be a dairy future ahead of us.
It costs Becky around 26p to produce a litre of milk and that's despite investing heavily in more cost-effective production, including the latest robotic milking machine.
This is one bit of technology that robots have - the camera that attaches to the units, which then films the udder to detect where the teats are in order to connect the unit.
This is laboursaving, as we don't have to get involved in putting the units on ourselves.
I feel that this farm is the most efficient that we can get to.
These robots, there isn't much that they don't pick up.
I know which cows haven't come in to be milked, I can tell how much they're milking each day, I can tell if they've got mastitis before signs start showing...
It's a very high standard of efficiency.
We aren't in this industry to make lots of money.
A year ago, this business would have been sustained, not a problem, with the price of the milk.
Unfortunately, since then, it's only come down.
All we're asking for is to make a living and look after our girls.
Exactly who is to blame for the current dairy crisis is far from clear-cut.
A dramatic drop in global prices has certainly had a major part to play, but for producers like Becky, British retailers and dairy processors make a real difference when they pay farmers more for a litre of milk.
To encourage them to do just that, farmers have been campaigning hard.
Becky has been involved in something called The Milk Trolley Challenge, and videos of their efforts have gone viral.
It seems to have had an effect.
The Milk Trolley Challenge is basically a group of farmers, or people supporting our industry, going into a supermarket that isn't paying fairly.
We take the milk completely off the shelves.
We then leave them in the trolleys, either dotted around the store, in front of the counters - we made a point of putting it in front of the water, as water is more expensive than milk.
That way, they were getting the message that we weren't happy with what prices they were selling our milk for.
The public's response has been fantastic - we've had support in the stores, we've had people videoing us, we've had people coming up to us saying they would be prepared to pay more for their milk, and that is exactly the response we were after.
In the past, there has been many protests about the milk price, and I think that the reason we have captured the public eye is because the younger generation have started this.
The main thing is that we've now had a response from the supermarkets, which is what we wanted to achieve.
They've now started talking to us, negotiating - we've had a step in the right direction.
Being new into the dairy industry and...from, obviously, the younger generation, it is...it is quite scary in the current situation we're in, whether I have got a future in farming.
I don't want to see these girls go, and I will keep fighting for them, but unless the supermarkets help and the price we get paid goes up, unfortunately, I can't see that being a bright future ahead of us.
So, would you pay more for your milk if that money was guaranteed to go to the farmers?
Let us know via our website... ..or share your thoughts on Twitter, using...
And you can follow us...
In Scotland, Tom's been looking at plans to change the way land is owned and managed.
He has already met the people who welcome the reforms.
Now, he's off to see those who aren't so keen.
From the Highland glens, down to the fertile Lowlands, half of Scotland's private land is owned by a tiny minority.
The Scottish government doesn't think that's very fair.
And, with the help of a controversial Land Reform Bill, they want to put more land in the hands of more people.
But many landowners and even estate workers think that could do more harm than good.
Landowners like Jamie Williamson - or, rather, the laird of Alvie and Dalraddy estate.
His family have owned these 13,000 acres for nearly a century, but the reforms could potentially force landowners like him to sell up to local communities.
Well, it's not a bad spot you brought me to.
So what, for you, is the significance of places like this?
Well, my family has owned and invested in this land for over 80 years.
Mm-hm.
So...and it's been very much a means now of making a living.
The oldest trees were planted in 1866 to 1877, felled in the 1980s, and we've replanted it and it'll be another 80 years before we get a full return from the trees.
So, the young trees, like the one behind me here, who will see a return from that?
Probably my grandson or my great-grandson.
Generations of Jamie's family have invested in this estate, ensuring its survival.
What problem do you have with the idea of communities having a right to buy?
It very much depends how far the government goes on this.
Obviously, we are concerned if a local community can say, "Oh, we rather like what you've got, we want it, we'll have it."
And this, because we're doing investment in the long term, would be a huge disincentive for us to continue investing, if we thought at any time anyone can come along and say, "Oh, we rather like what you've got."
As well as selling timber, farming and shooting, like many estates, Alvie and Dalraddy had to diversify.
'The latest problem in Jamie's caravan park 'is in the toilet block, 'and this laird isn't afraid to get his hands dirty.'
So, being a laird is not all tweed and glamour.
No, no - there is an awful lot of clearing blocked drains, etc, as well.
'Jamie is passionate about the job 'handed down to him by his forefathers.
'Under the reforms, he will probably hold on to his land.
'But because he gets income from shooting, 'he's likely to be hit in the pocket.'
At the moment, sporting estates are exempt from paying business-rate tax.
The Land Reform Bill will put an end to that.
'100 miles across the Cairngorms in Glenesk, 'fourth-generation gamekeeper Garry MacLennan 'earns a living from deer and grouse shooting.'
There you go.
'He's worried the plans to remove rate relief 'on sporting estates like his could hit hard, 'affecting the workers too.'
You know, the margins are very tight.
Quite often, they run at a loss.
The first thing that will happen is jobs are going to go.
So that's the real worry.
I've got a family to support, you know...
The knock-on effect of...
We've got a very small school in the area.
There's six pupils at present, so if we start losing jobs, families will go, and then, ultimately, the school could go.
The Scottish government haven't really thought it through - they've got this idea of, "Let's attack the rich", but really, they are affecting the working people that they're wanting to help.
Today, it's the village Highland Games - a chance for the locals to get together for a bit of light-hearted competition.
For Garry, like others on the estate, they don't feel the need to own their land in order to belong here.
You look at what's here today - you know, we're standing on land that's owned by the Earl, and look what it's getting used for.
So I think if you were to go and ask some of the people that are here, I think that they'll feel very much part of the estate and part of the community.
So, the SNP's vision of a fairer Scotland could be different to that of many rural communities, like the one here in Glenesk.
Is that not a concern for the minister leading the Land Reform Bill?
Clearly, the communities will very much be in the driving seat - if a community wants to take over land, the community will be in charge of its own destiny.
But what we have seen is where communities have taken over land, jobs are created - not scrapped, they are created, and therefore it is good for the local economy.
But some of these people feel more secure with the landlord they know, rather than a community that they don't.
If existing landowners are doing a good job for the local community and there's a good relationship with the local community, we don't see an issue with that - what we're doing is equipping the government on behalf of the public interest, to intervene where things aren't working.
If all goes according to plan for the SNP, the Land Reform Bill could become law within a year.
These mountains and glens have seen their fair share of conflict over the years, and now, it's the landowners who feel they're under attack.
The battle lines have been drawn and, over the next year, rural Scotland is going to see some fiery debate.
I've stepped away from Harewood House and the hubbub of the game fair to enjoy a tranquil moment or two.
This is the Himalayan Garden and, at its heart, there's something rather special.
The garden was restored a decade ago, overseen by the current Lord Harewood, David Lascelles.
In the 1930s, his ancestors sponsored plant hunters to bring back exotic species from Asia.
Since the restoration, the garden has blossomed.
But it's not a flower I'm here to see.
David is my guide.
Wow!
This is really quite incredible - not at all what I expected to see somewhere on your estate.
Well, this is a little bit of the Himalayas, brought to an English country garden.
It's a stupa, which is a Buddhist monument, which you'll find all over the Buddhist Himalayas.
Essentially, it represents a Buddhist concept of enlightenment and how to achieve it, a path to enlightenment.
So we have the architectural shape, the outer form, if you like.
It's a hollow monument, made of a series of five chambers, each of which are full of worldly goods.
In the bottom one, clothes, musical instruments, agricultural tools traditionally in the Himalayas, an agricultural community.
I put a camera in there, because I used to work in film and television.
And then, building up, each one is like a little shrine, I suppose, but sealed.
What is inside is what kind of gives...what energises the outer form.
So tranquil - the perfect place to escape the crowds.
What's it like having a huge show in your back garden?
Well, only once every few years, but it's great.
I love to see the place being used.
I come here quite often, one of my favourite spots.
It's always quiet, even when it's very, very busy, like it is at the moment, up by the house.
It's always quiet down here.
Here, in this corner of a busy Yorkshire estate, the perfect place to find a little solitude.
While we're at the game fair, Adam is also in Yorkshire for the latest of his films on our county breeds.
It fascinates me how, throughout the country, there are breeds particular to individual places.
Our livestock has been shaped by the landscape it lives in and the way we farm it.
So, today, I'm getting a closer look at seven county breeds that are special to Yorkshire.
When I think about the traditional breeds of Yorkshire, this is what springs to mind - Swaledale sheep, up here, about 1,000 feet up, on the weather-beaten hills of the Yorkshire Dales.
In fact, there are 30 times more sheep in the Yorkshire Dales than people - more than half a million of them.
They're hardy creatures, used to being out in all weathers.
'Roy Nelson has been a shepherd here all his working life.
'I've chosen to meet him on a day that shows why farmers here 'need to be tough, too.'
This is a good bit of Yorkshire weather, Roy, isn't it?
Aye - it just had to rain.
We've a marvellous view down there, if it'd been clear, but...it isn't, so that's that.
Why is it that Swaledale suits this region so well, then?
Well, they're just hardier.
Ours live out on t'top in winter, more or less same as they did 50 year ago, and grow to a size that they can support themselves.
So what should the ewe look like?
We like them with a good, hard coat on, a jacket and waistcoat...
LAUGHING What does that mean?
It wants to be a thick bed of wool that'll keep the wind out.
And then it wants a bit of top on it to throw the water off, so as we're like today...
Yeah, it just runs away.
And if you were out here all winter, the first thing you'd want would be a good, warm, dry top coat.
So, you've got these tough sheep up here - you've got to be a pretty hardy farmer too, haven't you?
I don't know - it's just what we're used to.
You just don't think about it.
Do you feel the sheep are part of you, as a Yorkshireman?
Oh, definitely, yes.
One of the biggest thrills to me is when somebody buys one off me, and then they take it to a show somewhere and they'll maybe win at a show with it.
I feel quite proud of that.
And the annual Ryedale Agricultural Show is just the place to see the best of this breed, in amongst 1,000 sheep exhibits.
Now, here we are - let me explain something to you.
That Swaledale ewe here, the female, not only is a fantastic sheep at surviving on the hills, but also, if she is crossed with this ram, the Bluefaced Leicester, this great big brute, put him on her, you get a lamb called a Mule.
And this is a Mule ewe - a wonderful mother.
So, she has fine wool, lots of lambs, plenty of milk from the Bluefaced Leicester and then that wonderful mothering ability and hardiness from the Swaledale.
It is an incredible mix that creates this fantastic sheep that is now the mainstay of lowland sheep farming, producing lamb for the table.
And that is why the Swaledale is the backbone of the UK sheep industry.
But Yorkshire is not just the birthplace of hardy sheep - it has some good lookers, too.
You've heard of Wensleydale cheese - well, this is the Wensleydale sheep.
This one is called Nosterfield Lulu 2.
She has just won Reserve Supreme Champion of Show for owner Ernie Sherwin.
How long have you been breeding Wensleydales?
They've been in the family for over a century, really, over the years, with my grandparents and my dad and things.
So you feel really passionate about them as a breed.
Yes, they're a bit of a fun thing.
I love to keep these traditional breeds on for their wool.
The fleeces are worth in excess of £100, now, in the right places.
Well, congratulations with her.
Beautiful.
They came from Wensleydale itself.
Yes, yeah.
The Cistercian monks are supposed to have set up with the Wensleydale creamery to start off milking them and making cheese, apparently.
So that's where the famous Wensleydale cheese comes from.
Yeah.
There are also 1,000 horses on show here, and there's one local breed I'm particularly interested in.
In the show ring now is the Cleveland Bay - they used to be known as "the Chapman horse".
The chapmen were the travelling salesman and they used these animals as pack horses, to carry all their wares around, and they were very versatile - they could pull the plough, they could be ridden or they'd pull carriages.
But sadly, now they're in decline and they're a rare breed.
This is another classic Yorkshire breed - the Middle White, with its lovely, squashed nose.
It was developed about 200 years ago by a guy called Joseph Tully in Keighley, West Riding.
They're great at producing pork.
But there is another breed of pig from Yorkshire that's become famous worldwide.
The Middle White's much bigger cousin is creatively called the Large White.
They used to be seen as the perfect pig, sent all over the world to establish commercial breeding herds, earning them a great reputation.
'They are still a favourite of Ron Fieldhouse, 'who breeds them on his farm in Tadcaster.'
Goodness me - how many piglets has she got?
13.
They are gorgeous!
Tell me about the breed itself.
Where did it originate from?
It originated in West Riding of Yorkshire and was quickly developed into a fast, lean-growing pig, suitable for the bacon trade and was exported worldwide.
And when was it at its height?
I would say it was at its height in the '50s, and then started declining in the late '70s, when the breeding companies started developing hybrids, which are basically a mixture of Large White and other breeds.
Do you think they still have their place?
They still have their place, yes - they are still a fast, lean-growing pig that can compete with the commercial market.
We call them Large Whites, but worldwide, they're known as the Yorkshire pig.
Lovely - how does that make you feel?
Oh, very proud.
Despite the recent decline, it's hybrids of the breed that are used by the large-scale producers to supply supermarkets.
They are big pigs, aren't they?
Yes.
'And here in Yorkshire, the purebred Large Whites 'are in safe hands.
'Ron's son David is building up the herd to help preserve them.'
We've seen that there is going to be a real problem, because people just aren't breeding them, so there are a few of us that are just trying to get them out and get them spread throughout the country.
Do you keep them because they're a good pig, or because they're Yorkshire pigs and you're a Yorkshireman?
It's a bit of both, really.
I mean, there is pride in it that they are the Yorkshire breed and we are based in Yorkshire, so what better pig to keep?
Yorkshire's local breeds have spread their influence far beyond the farmyard.
Bred here in the 1860s for hunting, the Airedale terrier became a hero of the First World War.
They were trained to find wounded soldiers and carry messages.
'But it is one of the world's smallest dogs 'that is the best-known Yorkshire breed of all.'
Why have you chosen to keep Yorkshire terriers?
Because they are a nice little dog - the hairs don't drop out, and they're...
Come on!
They're sporting.
She does the ratting and very good at ratting and this little one that's hanging back - come on, mate - I use her for my deerstalking.
She finds all the deer and the rabbits that I shoot.
Really?
Proper little working dogs, then.
Proper working dogs.
How did they come about?
Why Yorkshire terriers in Yorkshire?
Well, they were bred initially for keeping the rat population down in the mills.
And there would have been a lot mills round here.
Hundreds.
Hundreds of mills, yes.
I suppose, as a little dog, they can get into all the nooks and crannies and...
Yes.
..And get in and catch rats.
Lightning quick as well.
They have got a bit of a reputation as being a handbag breed - have they been bred smaller for that?
Yes - an old lady's dog.
But they're not.
They will tackle any dog when they're out on a walk, with or without the ribbons in their hair.
ADAM LAUGHS They've got a big attitude for a little animal.
They have got a big attitude.
They can be a bit snappy, can't they, sometimes?
This one has never bitten anybody, yet...
There's always a first time!
Always a first time.
Tiny dogs, enormous pigs, versatile work horses - Yorkshire has given us so much.
But, for me, this is the image that defines the county.
A man, a dog, and a flock of Swaledale sheep - the romance and the grit of farming in Yorkshire.
You probably get the idea by now - the CLA Game Fair really is the place to be for those passionate about country sports.
I really feel as though I've entered the belly of rural life.
This is proper, tweed-wearing, hunting, shooting, fishing territory.
The shooting line here is the longest in Europe, and it gets busy - at its peak, 4,000 shots each hour.
There are competitions for the world's best, as well as a chance for anyone to come and have a go.
Believe it or not, guns have never really featured in my life, but I've been challenged to a friendly competition by a local club.
Apparently, I'm just the sort of person they want to recruit, so I'd better get some practice in.
Mark Windsor is a true sharpshooter - one of England's best.
He's got 20 years' experience under his belt, and it shows.
He also happens to be one of the best coaches in the country, so I reckon I'll be in safe hands.
OK - what we are going to do, before we do anything with this gun, before we fire it at all, we're going to do a dry run, OK?
Sure.
We are basically going to simulate what is going to happen when you actually use the live shot.
So we are live, now.
OK.
Pull.
OK, so follow it up to the middle - bang.
No!
That was all over the place.
It doesn't matter.
That's why we do a dry run.
Take the safety off.
OK.
It's fast, isn't it?
Yes, it is pretty fast.
But the one thing I will ask, OK, is you don't do too much movement with the gun.
Sure.
'Right - let's do this for real.'
GUNSHOT OK.
Whoa!
Well done.
Didn't hit anything - let's try it again.
OK.
So, we're live.
Pull.
Here it comes - straight to the middle.
GUNSHOT Yes!
Lovely.
Within two shots, we have a broken target.
'Well, it's a good start.
'But there's a way to go before I'm a true contender.'
GUNSHOT Oh...
Look at that - absolutely fantastic.
GUNSHOT So, that was slightly left-handed...
GUNSHOT Ooh...
So satisfying.
GUNSHOT Yes!
Well shot - brilliant!
Ha...
Yeah.
Well, I'm having fun.
I think I need a little bit more practice before I enter this competition.
I can't believe I'm entering a competition.
You're doing really well.
Why am I entering a competition?
OK - so, I've busted a few clays.
GUNSHOT Perfect.
But back at the fair, there are some super sharpshooters.
Pull - fire.
Wow!
Rachel, that was seriously impressive.
Thank you.
I'm guessing this is no ordinary shooting club.
No - we are Femmes Fatales, we are a ladies-only shooting club.
Girls only?
Girls only.
Not the first thing you think about - I know this might sound sexist - but girls and guns?
What's the appeal?
It's exciting, it's something social - we all get together.
There are so many girls that take part already.
There's been a huge influx over the last few years.
It's our passion.
We love it.
Is this something woman can do equally as well as men?
There are no physical limitations as to why women can't be just as good, if not better, than men at shooting.
It's not hugely physically demanding, anybody can do it - it doesn't matter what size you are, what age you are.
Men and women, we can all do it together and, you know, shooting competitively, we all sort of compete on a level pegging.
And is it just...people who live in the countryside?
Is that who shooting is for?
That is exactly the opposite aim of Femmes Fatales - it's just to appeal to everyone, from all walks of life.
It's brilliant to see, actually - it's not all tweed and flat caps.
Right - the moment of truth.
Three women, three clays, three shots each.
It...is...on.
Three, two, one - pull.
ANITA LAUGHS Excellent - fantastic.
One down.
Pull.
So far, so good.
That's two out of two for me.
But that's a miss for the competition.
And another.
Pull.
Oh, well done - she got it.
'So, it's down to my last shot.
This is for the win.'
Exactly the same again, what you just did.
Just do exactly the same again.
Amazing!
Perfect shooting.
I can't believe that!
Thank you so much.
Three out of three.
You are therefore the Femmes Fatales Countryfile Challenge winner.
Congratulations!
Amazing - thank you, what an honour.
You're an absolute natural.
You've definitely got a future in competitive shooting.
And you may well have another member.
We'd love to see you at our events - we'd love to have you back.
Thanks for coming.
It's been brilliant.
I love it.
I can't believe I have got a proper little trophy.
Now, clays are one thing, but if you're after game birds, as well as a steady hand and a good eye, it's a gundog you will need.
Come on!
WHISTLE BLOWS Fiercely intelligent, energetic and bred and trained to obey, gundogs are masters of the shoot.
Out in the field, they are essential, helping to flush out and retrieve game birds.
With the right handler, they can reach the top of their game.
Which I'm not sure can be said of this pampered pooch.
Meet Oscar - he's our family golden retriever.
We've had him since he was a puppy.
He's a bit eccentric, but he can be smart on his day.
I am just not sure he's gundog material.
But I could be wrong and today, we're going to find out what he's capable of.
Come on, mate.
But first, I want to see an expert in action.
So, I'm leaving the fair and heading to a nearby village, where I'm meeting someone who really knows her stuff.
She is one of the best young handlers in the country.
She's put four gundogs through their paces and she even competes against adults.
Meet Siobhan, who's 11 years old.
Hey, Siobhan.
How are you doing?
OK.
Who is this handsome chap?
Sammy.
Nice to meet you, Sammy.
Talk me through what you do with Sammy, then.
Well, my mum will throw a mark out.
I'll send him back.
There it goes.
Yeah, and, when I send him, he should go straight back and then come back.
OK.
So what are you doing with the whistle, now?
Well, that first whistle I did, that was my hunt whistle, and then the second one was my call-back whistle.
Good boy.
Look at that.
So, was that a good one?
Are you happy with that?
Yeah.
Does he do that for anyone?
Could I whistle and call him and he'd do it for me?
No, he won't do it for my mum and he won't do it for my dad.
Oh, really?
No, because he's like...
He's a bit of a wimp, sometimes.
He doesn't look like a wimp to me.
Looks like a commanding, fine dog.
I tell you what, he'll make my dog look like a wimp.
He's very good.
Siobhan will be going all out at the fair to add yet another trophy to her collection.
Good boy, Sammy.
Oscar, Come on...
Oscar and I have got quite a bit of work to do to get anywhere near THAT standard.
There's one person, though, who might be able to help us.
Hello, Pippa.
Hello, nice to see you.
And who is this young man?
This is Oscar.
I'm hoping you can be responsible for bringing the retriever out of him.
No, I'm a people teacher, Joe.
I'm going to teach YOU.
Oh, right...
It's YOUR job to teach HIM.
OK.
Well, I think we need to get him playing with his toy a little bit.
So you want to keep it nice and jolly, nice and light.
Just let him have a little play, let him catch it, and we'll just see what his response is to it.
You've got to be a bit more exciting than that, Joe.
You've got to be much bigger.
Yeah, so you've got to run up and down.
Oscar, come on.
And, now, give him a sausage.
Lovely.
And let catch his toy.
Chuck it up in the air.
Oscar.
Well, as they say, if at first you don't succeed, try, try again.
And again...
And again.
Oscar's gone to take his toy off.
He's quite a selfish retriever.
So, after a good half hour's instruction, we decide Oscar's ready for a retrieve.
It's the job his breed is supposed to excel at, after all.
Good boy!
Well done!
Oscar, come.
Good lad.
A flying puffin.
Oscar, come.
Well done.
Good lad.
Not breaking any speed records.
Oscar, come.
Nearly.
Oh, yes!
Well done.
Superb.
And fast.
Good boy.
That deserves a bit of sausage.
Well done.
How important is it to keep a dog like Oscar stimulated?
Oh, very important, because you need to keep him mentally as well as physically fit.
So, what do you think?
With a little bit of training, some potential there?
A BIT of training, Joe?
I think a lot of training on your behalf!
We have to put that work in, and then we get the response and we get the rewards come out of it.
So, look, it's getting a bit late in the day for him, he's a bit lethargic, but we've seen some progress, haven't we?
We've definitely improved on his recall.
He's actually retrieving now, so we're getting there.
But how will Oscar do when we really put him to the test in just a moment?
We're at the CLA Game Fair, one of the biggest events in the rural calendar, coming, this year, from the grand setting of Harewood House in West Yorkshire.
It's a hard life being a dog - long walks, warm beds, tasty treats.
And, to be honest, that's pretty much Oscar's limit, but, today at the fair, we're going to find out if he can do what his breed is actually supposed to - retrieve.
He's already had some expert training.
Now for the ultimate test - head-to-head with his nemesis, Sammy the black Labrador.
How are you doing, Siobhan?
OK.
Good to see it all happening in this arena.
Now, you've been competing today, haven't you?
Yeah.
I've been doing some scurries and I've been doing the scramble.
Siobhan's won two rosettes today.
Let's see how a top dog does it.
So, Oscar, this guy's something of a champion, so pay really close attention, OK?
Good boy.
Fetch it.
Very good.
With Sammy and Siobhan looking on, now it's our turn.
Don't let me down, Oscar!
We've been struggling a little bit with Oscar's training.
The moment of truth.
Oscar, this is what your half an hour's training has been all about, OK?
Oscar?
Right, here we go.
Here we go.
Look this way.
Here's the mark.
Ready?
That's it.
Go on!
Go on.
Yes!
The green thing, Oscar!
Oh, dearie me.
So close.
And that, I have to say, is the difference between half an hour's training and a good two and a half years.
So, well done, Siobhan, and good luck.
Oh!
Well done!
Hey, Joe, how did Oscar do?
We've had a breakthrough, but I think it's fair to say he's not in danger of winning any trophies here.
No.
Well, somebody did.
Look at that!
Oh, no way!
You sharpshooter!
Apparently so.
Apparently, I might have to take it up.
Oh, well done.
Well, that's it from this year's CLA Game Fair.
Join us next week when we'll be in Powys in Mid Wales...
Where Matt will really have his work cut out and I'm meeting some cattle who have a taste for beer.